In this video, I'm going to show you how
to build SEO super intelligence so you
can get results like this, this, and
this. My name is Nathan Gotch, and I've
led thousands of successful SEO
campaigns over the last decade, and I'm
the author of the upcoming book AI SEO
for Dummies. So, let's begin with step
number one, which is to understand what
SEO super intelligence actually is. So,
I'll be walking you through a real-life
example of how to set up this SEO super
intelligence, but first, let me show you
the component pieces of what we're going
to be building today. So, first things
first is you need a raw intelligence
layer. And so, you really want to use
the best models that currently exist.
So, I just picked three here as an
example, but Fable, which is from
Claude, Opus, which is also from Claude,
and then Soul, which comes from OpenAI.
Truthfully, you can use pretty much any
model these days and get really good
outputs. You could even use Grok.
Really, at the end of the day, they're
all very intelligent, and the thing that
makes this work really well is not the
particular model that you're going to
pick, although that certainly does help.
What really matters is all of the
component pieces that we're going to be
feeding into this intelligence. But
first, pick a raw intelligence layer.
I'll be showing you how to do that in a
second. Next is going to be your data.
So, you want to pipe in as much data in
as you possibly can. So, you want Google
Search Console, you want Google
Analytics 4. If you're doing local, you
want to pipe in that Google Business
Profile data. If you want to go to the
next level, I would also try to bring in
YouTube and Microsoft Clarity or some
sort of user tracking software that you
may already have. And then, of course,
bring in any keyword tracking data,
whether you're tracking AI or tracking
traditional search, I would bring both
of those in there as well. And then, you
want to bring in the brand intelligence.
So, that's going to be anything related
to the products and services that you
sell, the frequently asked questions,
policies, brand voice, all kinds of
stuff that we're going to be talking
about in this video. And then, the one
of the most important pieces of this is
bringing in your expertise and
experience in this particular industry.
So, the best way to do this is
interview the founders or the subject
matter experts of the business,
transcribe, and then feed that into the
intelligence layer. I'll be showing you
how to streamline this and do this in
the right way. Most people don't do this
right. They just dump a bunch of
information into this, and it will cause
a lot of problems. And then, we want to
bring in competitor intelligence. So, we
focus a lot on our brand and our
foundation, but now we want to look
externally at who we're up against. One
of my favorite things to do is just look
at the competitors that are doing really
well in search, and then build
frameworks based on what's already
working. I'll show you how to do that in
this video. And then, finally,
execution. Almost no one talks about
this, and this is like the hidden secret
power of doing effective SEO is every
single action that you take in your
campaign, you want to create a record of
that because that allows the AI to go
back and reference that record over and
over. So, it can cross-check and then
ultimately be able to give you diagnosis
as to why something did well or why
something actually didn't do well. You
need to have that record, and it's so
important. So, in this video, I'm going
to be walking you through all the
component pieces of this to ultimately
build this super intelligence for your
SEO campaign. And keep in mind, what
we're doing here today is just the
foundation, and this is the key to
really building a powerful SEO campaign.
And then, in the following videos, it's
going to be a full series, but we're
just beginning with SEO super
intelligence. The next couple of videos,
we're going to focus more on building
even more foundational layers. So, it's
going to be keyword research, deeper
competitor analysis, and so on and so
forth. It's going to be probably about
10 to 11 videos in this series. But for
this first one, think of this as your
base layer for your campaign, and this
is what's going to help you take it to
the next level. Doesn't matter whether
you're doing this for your own business
or you're doing this for your clients,
this will work. So, let's get into it.
All right, so the first step of this
process is to simply pick between either
Codex  ChatGPT or Claude, okay? I
use both on a daily basis and I can tell
you they're both incredibly intelligent.
This is not what is going to make the
difference in your success in your SEO
campaign. So, I'm telling you, just pick
one that you like using and then go with
it. It's really all of the other
ingredients of this process that will
determine the success of your campaign,
okay? So, what you want to do here is
very simply, if you're using Codex, I'm
not going to use both of these
throughout this video. I'll just pick
one of them and show you, but just for
the sake of this setup, you're going to
go ahead over here into projects and go
ahead and just click the little plus
button if you're in Codex, and then just
go ahead and create a project, okay? So,
this is going to be the test project
we'll be doing in this series, and we're
going to go ahead and just create
project, and now we've got the project
in place, and what this is going to
allow us to do is every single chat that
we have can be retained within this
project, okay? That's very important.
And then we can also, when we go in the
local level, we can actually go ahead
and add a folder in here as well. So,
you see I've got a folder in here. This
is where I'm going to store all of the
files for this campaign, so that way the
AI always has that context, okay? Now,
same thing in Claude, simply just go to
new project, go like this, and then
we're going to go ahead and just create
that project, okay? And same thing here,
you're going to go ahead and you can add
all of the files in here for context.
Once again, all of those files will be
stored in a folder on my computer
desktop. That is really important
because that gives you flexibility on
what model you want to use, okay? I'm
not a big fan of storing everything on
these providers. I want to have the
freedom to move wherever I want to go.
Maybe I want to use Codex, maybe I want
to use Claude, maybe I want to use
perplexity. Whatever it is, okay? You
need to control your resources. So,
control it on your desktop or whatever.
It could be in Google Drive. Doesn't
make a difference. But, really if you
want full control, like you technically
wouldn't even use Google Drive. You
would just only use your computer to
retain those files. And that way these
AI providers don't own your stuff, okay?
But, regardless, we want a structured
project that we can work in. And then
the next following parts of this process
we're going to start to build the
foundation and the ingredients to build
this superintelligence. All right. So,
the first step in the process is we're
going to establish the brand
intelligence layer. So, on the left-hand
side, you can see I've got a setup for
Claude. And on the right-hand side is
the website that we're going to be using
in this particular example, okay? So, a
couple things just to kind of clarify
some points.
There's You can go super crazy on this
part, but I would recommend just getting
a nice base level of brand intelligence.
You really only need about five
artifacts. An artifact is simply a
document. It's some sort of thing that
is produced. So, that's really AI
language, but it's really just a
markdown file. And so, what we're doing
here is you can see I've got these four
markdown files that are templates, okay?
And then I've got a little description
of what I want it to do. So, I think
this is important to kind of clarify
here. So, basically what I'm telling the
AI to do
is I want it to build these artifacts
and then put these artifacts into the
folder on my desktop. I've given it very
specific information. So, the website,
the brand, and it's very important also
add aliases in here, okay? This is a big
mistake I see a lot of people make is
when you start to do SEO, you want to
make sure you've got the full brand
identity established. Because when we go
and do a brand consistency audit, we
need to make sure we understand
everything about the brand, okay? Now,
if you're working with the client, you
should collect this information up
front. But, clients do forget to
sometimes tell you information, so you
need to do additional research. We'll
talk more about that later. And then, of
course, the location that you're going
after. In this case, this is a local
business, so it's going to be St. Louis.
And then, most importantly, giving it
very specific instructions about what I
want it to do. I want it to build the
first four artifacts, which really gives
the AI context.
And then, the final artifact that I want
to build is this entity record. This is
so critical because this record, treat
it as your source of truth in the
campaign. It is the most important
record, and when you go and you start to
audit the different assets online for
that particular brand, and trying to
find inconsistencies, you always go back
to that source of truth as being able to
cross-check to see if it's consistent.
Okay, so you need that record. It's so
important for later stages in this
process. What we're going to do now is
we're going to go ahead and run this,
and then I'm going to show you what the
AI will produce, what it will spit out
in this process. All right, so Claude is
pretty much done at this point, so I'll
just quickly walk you through the files
that we've created. So, couple key
things here. I just want to make sure
that we're not overestimating the
capabilities
of Claude, okay? One thing that is very
dangerous is when you watch it work like
this, you watch it build these markdown
files, you watch it create all this
content, it's easy to get kind of
persuaded into thinking that these are
all facts. This is all accurate
information, and that is not true. The
AI can still hallucinate. The AI can
still pull from sources and use that
information and treat it as law or fact,
okay? It is simply taking in all the
information from web search, and then
spitting that out. Now, it's gotten a
lot better at this. Hallucination rates
are extra a lot lower than they were a
couple of years ago, and it's not likely
to do that very frequently, but it is
still a danger and a risk. So, even when
you build out these files, you still
want to take some time, have a human in
the loop to go through and actually see
what's going on, okay? So, especially
with the entity record, all right? So,
what we can see here is within about I
think it took about maybe about 20
minutes, it went and built out all of
these artifacts. So, we can see here the
campaign strategy artifact. You can see
it's quite comprehensive. Now, we're
going to be building a far bigger
strategy than what it outlined here, but
it's still useful. It's going to
actually give you a really good baseline
to work from if you're kind of newer to
SEO. This can certainly give you a good
place to start, but we're going to be
taking this to the next level. A small
little detail here, which is very
important to understand, it is making
assumptions without any quantifiable
data, okay? That already creates a
flawed environment, okay? So, be very
careful with the recommendations here.
These are general recommendations
without any data, without any grounding
whatsoever. So, be very careful, but
this, like I said, this is just to get
you a good base.
And then we look at the brand voice.
This brand voice is built just by
analyzing the website, all right? So,
it's building the way it's looking at it
from the website and then building out
that brand voice. Once again, this is an
area that you want to spend some time on
to make sure that it's correct because
we're going to be using these files to
actually build content in later videos
in this series. So, this little
foundation part here, like spending the
extra time to make sure this is all
good, is really worth time spent, okay?
You can see very deep here on the
offers. Once again, this is all just
extracted from the website. We've got
the business profile here, which
basically just outlines all the offers
and everything else related to this
brand. And then we've got the offers,
which once again, this is all just
related to the services that this agency
provides, okay? And then the final piece
of this is the entity record. So, this
one, like I said, is the source of
truth. If you're going to spend any time
digging into this, this is the one you
want to spend some time on. Go line by
line, use your human insights, your
understanding of this brand, and spend
some time making sure that this is all
accurate, okay? This is a lot of
information, okay? This is what the AI
does. It gives you ton of information,
but a lot of the time it's fluffed up,
and a lot of the time it's inaccurate.
So, be really careful here. Do not be
persuaded by this information. Make sure
that you have a human in the loop to
make sure that this is right, because
you don't want to start launching a
campaign and start spreading a bunch of
misinformation, which is actually going
to have adverse effects on your
performance in the AI platforms, okay?
But, this gives you the nice base to
work from, and you can see all of those
files were put into the folder that we
created in the earlier step. So, now
this is our information. This is not
Claude's information. I can take this
exact MD file and all of this
information here, and I could go right
into Codex and run this same exact play.
I could go into Perplexity. I could go
to Gorok. I can go anywhere I want,
because this is the source of truth.
These documents are for the campaign,
and now that allows me to go wherever I
want, use whatever AI I please, and
ultimately gives you tons of flexibility
in your campaign. So, this is the very
first step of this process. So, now that
we've got our nice brand intelligence
layer built out, we're going to take
this to the next level, and we're going
to start to extract insights from
subject matter experts who work at the
business. All right, so the next step in
this process is to bring in real
experience and expertise into this
foundation that we're building. So, if
you're working with a plumber, or you're
working with an e-comm company, you got
to identify the subject matter expert
who works at that business. So, that
might be you, that might be someone
else, but regardless, you got to
identify who those one to three people
are. And from there, you have a couple
options. Number one is you can actually
conduct an SME interview, so a subject
matter expert interview. And
essentially, you just set up a meeting
on Zoom or Google Meet. You ask them a
bunch of questions. You could of course
have AI develop the questionnaire and
the questions to ask specifically. And
then you record that session, and then
you take that transcript, and you bring
it over here into Claude. Now, here is
the mistake that people make, okay? So,
this example I'll be using an interview
that I have. So, this is another thing
you can do if you can go and scour the
internet and find interviews with that
subject matter expert. You can feed that
in to get that kind of unique nuance
that you could never capture anywhere
else, okay?
But here is the thing you don't want to
do. You don't want to take that whole
transcript, that raw transcript, and
just throw it into your knowledge base,
okay? I'm only saying this because I've
learned from my mistakes.
And this is there's actually a a logical
reason for this. And it's because you
want to make retrieval easy for AI,
okay? And so, what does that mean? It
means when you conduct a when you ask a
question, you ask the AI to go and do
something, you want it to be able to
find that grounding, that information
that you've put into your knowledge base
very easily. And that will help prevent
hallucination and all kinds of other
issues that arise. So, how do we do it?
Okay, so there is a manual way of doing
this, and I use a tool. So, I'll show
you both ways.
Okay, so what you go let's say in a
YouTube video like this, I'm going to go
over here, I'm going to open this up,
and I'm going to go down here and go to
show transcript, okay? And then what you
can do is you can actually just go right
up here and just grab this entire
transcript. This is literally the whole
transcript from the video, okay? You can
also use Notebook LM to do this as well,
by the way, right? But if you don't want
to you just want to do it real quickly,
you just grab this, copy it over, we'll
paste it in here, and then I'll just
give a very simple command to Claude.
I need you to convert
this transcript into a structured
artifact that will go into the folder on
my desktop so that it's built for
effective retrieval.
Okay, so you can see I went ahead and
just popped that in there. And now what
it's going to do is it's going to
structure that artifact so it's nice and
clean, okay? And so there's like I said,
you can go and just copy this and go
into Notebook LM
and you can simply just go to create new
and then we'll go over to the YouTube
one. We'll just drop that in there.
And then this will automatically extract
that transcript, okay?
All right, so Claude is asking a
question here. Content source material.
Yeah.
Let's see here. It's trying to mostly
about Rankbility AI and I Okay, the
purpose of this artifact is to extract
the experience and expertise and nuance
from Nathan Gotch.
Okay, so you can see I've added a little
additional context so that the AI
understands what I'm actually trying to
do here. But this is obviously it's
confusing with what I'm doing cuz I'm
talking about SEO and then doing it The
whole thing's really confusing. So it'd
be a lot more straightforward if you're
working with a plumber and you're just
like, "Here's this plumber expertise and
experience in here." The AI will have a
lot easier understanding. You have to
keep in mind this project here has a
bunch of memory and history with me
working on Rankbility and working on all
of my projects. So it's not exactly how
it will be for you, okay? But the
general system will work, okay? So what
it will do is it's going to build out
that structured artifact and then you're
going to be able It should automatically
put that into the folder for us, okay?
It should actually appear in here. Now,
you can do the same thing over here in
Notebook LM. You can see that it
actually is showing the summary of this,
but you can get the whole transcript
here as well, okay? So once again,
either way is fine. One tool that I
actually use for myself internally, this
tool is not available to the public
right now. I might make it available at
some point, but right now basically what
I do is I just go over here, I copy this
over, and I go to this little tool that
I built, and it will just go ahead and
create a context file. So, it will
compress all of that content into a very
structured artifact. And so, you can see
I've already done a couple of here. So,
this particular interview was like 2
hours long. It condensed it down into
about 2,900 words. So, it's significant
distillation, right? And that's really
what you want to see because you don't
need all of that fluff in your knowledge
base. You want it to be really lean,
extremely retrievable, and really built
just purely optimized in that way. All
right, so you can see the tool went
ahead and did this. We can go ahead and
just download it.
And you can see the file here. My tool
actually did it much faster than Claude
is doing, and you can see much quicker,
already done, has a source, good to go,
right? And it Claude is still working on
this. So, this is an example where using
AI for everything is not always the
smartest idea. There's certain times
where you want to use AI where it's
requires a lot of reasoning, a lot of
thinking. That's all good, but there's
times when AI is actually the least
cost-efficient mechanism for certain
things. So, that's more like
deterministic type of systems, okay?
When you don't need excessive reasoning.
This is an example where you can very
use very light AI systems to produce
this particular outcome. And you can see
what I'm doing right now with Claude is
absolute overkill. Okay, you can see
Claude is going absolutely crazy. It's
cooking credits like you wouldn't
believe, and this is going to be an
insanely expensive operation to use Opus
5. So, this is an example where this is
major overkill, and most people
absolutely cook their tokens for no
reason because they're using Opus or the
most powerful model to do simple tasks,
kind of deterministic tasks. That's just
not what you want to do. You really want
to use these models for anything that
requires a lot of reasoning, a lot of
processing of inputs. That's where the
real magic happens. But what we're doing
here is very wasteful, okay? And that's
why I built a tool to solve that problem
because this is all just a bunch of
waste, all right? And an example of this
is actually great. This is 10,000 words.
It actually extracted down to 2,100. And
you can see it did it in like 1% of the
time that Claude is taking, and I can
guarantee that the output is going to be
almost exactly the same, okay? So, that
is what you want to do though. At a high
level, you need to get try to get at
least three to five of these kind of
experience/expertise
artifacts into your folder. And that
way, and the reason we're really doing
this is so when we create content, that
content will sound just like the brand.
We'll have those nuances, that
expertise, and so on and so forth. It's
not going to displace humans, and you're
not going to need human writers. That's
not the case at all. But it's setting
you up for a foundation where when we
pump out that first draft, it is already
better than anything that you could
produce just by slopping it up with
ChatGPT, okay? If you just run into
ChatGPT and say "Write me an article,"
it's going to be AI slop that will never
compete with this. So, just by taking
this initial doing this initial work,
this initial foundational work, I am
telling you your content, your SEO
campaign is going to be light-years
ahead of your competition. Okay, so your
brand intelligence foundation is set.
Now, what you want to do is pipe in all
of the existing data that you have for
this particular website. So, there's a
few data sources I would highly
recommend trying to bring in, which
would be Google Search Console, Google
Analytics 4. If you have Bing Webmaster
Tools, I'd also bring that in as well.
And then if you have any type of user
tracking software, it'd be like
Microsoft Copilot or Microsoft Clarity
or Hotjar or Mouseflow, any of those,
try to bring that data in as well. You
want to try to have as many different
data points as you can, and then plus,
whatever type of rank tracker you're
using to track your traditional search
rankings and your AI visibility as far
as brand mentions and AI citations in
AI. So, you want to bring that all in
and give you as much rich data as
possible. Now,
there's a slow way of doing this and a
fast way of doing this, but I'm going to
show you the most cost-effective way of
doing this. Not necessarily the most
scalable, it's not the easiest, but it
can be done, okay? So, basically, what
you want to do here is you can go right
into Google Search Console, all right?
Just go right into Google Search Console
and just set it to 16 months and export,
okay? Now, there's some downsides of
doing this. Number one is you don't
actually get to export every query. So,
when you do an export like this, it's
just giving you a a sample of your
queries, only a thousand in this case,
okay? So, there's a few workarounds.
Number one is you can go to each
individual page. So, for example, if I
want to extract more topic ideas, I
might go to the service page like this,
okay? And then I would extract from
here, and you can see there's only 102
queries for this one page. So, this is
extremely time-consuming to go and
extract each individual URL, but like I
said, it can be done, all right? So,
that's the slow way. The faster way is
to sign up for a Google Cloud. I
shouldn't say this is faster, it the
setup is longer. It's going to take
longer for you to get set up. It's going
to take definitely more time investment
and work to get it where it needs to be,
but once it's in a good place, you can
use the API, the Google Search Console
API, and you can pull that data into
Cloud, okay? And that allows you
actually to get up to 50,000 queries
compared to just the thousand that
you'll get in this case, okay? And
50,000 is a ton, all right? So, those
are kind of the two techniques you can
use. So, I'll show you an example. I
just did the very basic one so we don't
go super crazy here, and I just
downloaded the report and then I put it
into the folder. So, we'll go back here.
You can see I've got Google Search
Console with the date, and it's got all
of the data in here. So, you can see
we've got nice structure in here, right?
We've got our nice brand foundation,
we've got Google Search Console. Every
time you do a Google Search Console
import, just make sure you're labeling
it so you stay nice and organized, and
that helps even helps the AI stay
organized as well and not hallucinate,
okay? So, that is all you want to do.
And then over here, you could just do a
quick cross-check and just do an example
like, "Give me a quick analysis of the
Google Search Console data that I just
uploaded to the folder."
And it's going to go into the folder,
it's going to assess that data, and it's
going to give you some feedback on that
data. This is so important because what
we've done now is we took basically all
of the accessible information about
Let's see here.
So, what's happening now is we built all
that brand intelligence. Now, what we're
doing is we're using real data, real
grounding with the AI and layering that
in. And so, that's going to make the AI
so much more intelligent. And imagine if
you bring in Google Analytics, you bring
in Microsoft Clarity, you bring in Bing
Webmaster Tools, and whatever rank
tracking software you have, you are just
going to absolutely have so much rich
data to play with, and the AI is just
going to be able to use that to its
advantage to understand and ultimately
help you build a good strategy. Okay, so
this is a really good example of where
AI kind of falls short, and you can see
it is saying lots of stuff, but it
doesn't even know how to fix this stuff,
okay? So, that's the one thing that it
is really hard to replace a human in
this case. It's really good at the
foundational stuff, it's good at
creating content, it's good at some
execution level things, but it's
actually not that good at strategy. And
that's why in later in this series, I'm
going to be showing you how to take all
this work we've done today and build a
real 90-day SEO strategy. AI can't do
this. I'm just going to tell you now, AI
can't build a strategy like I'm going to
be showing you. There's just It just
can't do it. And trust me, I've tried.
It just can't do it. But what it can do
is it can help us
probe. It can help us dig into the data.
And if you know the right questions to
ask, you know the right things to look
for, that's where it becomes really
powerful. So,
whatever method you use, bring this data
in. It's going to make this SEO super
intelligence even more possible. All
right, so the last but most
time-consuming part of this process is
to build a swipe file, okay? And you're
not going to see many people talking
about this, but I am telling you if you
take the time to do this, you are going
to greatly elevate your content and your
SEO results greater than your
competitors. I cannot stress it enough.
Your competitors will not do this. They
already won't do the stuff we've already
done in this video, let alone what I'm
about to show you, okay? So, very
simple. You're going to go and look at
keywords in the vertical that you're
competing in. So, just run anywhere
between five to 10 keywords that are
really important in the industry that
you're competing in, okay? So, in this
case, I just did a really simple one,
best SEO consultants right now. And then
I look I grabbed a couple of pages here.
So, the first one here is this one. Now,
what I'm doing is I'm looking for the
top two to three pages per keyword. And
so, if you repeat this for anywhere
between, let's say, five to 10 keywords,
you're going to start to build a nice
pool of the assets that are proven to
work across search. And if you want to
get crazy on this, you can go and look
in AI as well. So, run these exact
queries
in ChatGPT, in Perplexity, in Claude,
whatever it may be. Extract the
citations out of there, and then
identify the URLs that are not only
ranking well in traditional search but
also are being used as a top source of
retrieval. You want to see both of those
together. If you see that, that's the
URL that you want to build a swipe file
for. Okay, so what does that mean? What
is a swipe file? All right. So, what you
don't want to do is just look at this
content that's performing exceptionally
well and copy it. That's not what we're
trying to do, okay? You're not going to
come in here and just copy what they're
doing. You're not going to beat them
just by copying them, okay? What we're
trying to do is we're trying to build
templates. There's a certain type of
template that tends to work in this
industry for each particular keyword
that you're going after. So, in this
case, clearly listicles work really
well, okay? Structured listicles that
have rich data tend to work really well.
I can visually see that right away just
by looking at it, right? But, I want to
systematize this more. So, basically
what you're going to do is because
obviously this would take a long time
and be very boring to watch me do this,
I'm just going to do one, okay? So,
we're going to throw this in here just
like this. And then what we're going to
do is you're just going to use this
prompt that I already built for you,
okay? So, you're just going to copy this
and you actually don't even need to put
in the details like this. It's already
pretty will just automatically
understand if you just kind of slap it
in there. But, if you want, you can
certainly do that, right? So, we'll just
for the sake of this, we'll just keep
it. We'll be really structured about
this, but the AI can pick it up, right?
It can pick it up well. So, in this
case, we're going to do I'm sorry, miss
you campaign in the SEO niche. We'll
make sure in St. Louis.
And then we'll go out and paste the URL
in here. Now, sometimes if Claude gets
blocked, it's not going to be able to
extract that content, okay? So, that's
why I'm not doing clutch cuz clutch is
probably going to block us. And by the
way, there's workarounds for that. I'm
not that's outside the scope of this
video, but I'll just tell you right now
to keep it simple, if you can't get that
content can't get Quad to extract that
content, just go straight to the page
and just literally copy the content.
That's simple. Then paste it in here,
okay? For this one, we're going to look
at we'll just do best SEO consultants
right now, okay?
And then, this one says, okay, yeah. And
then yeah, you don't really have to do
that, okay? You can just keep that one.
You don't have This is if you're going
super hardcore, okay?
All right. So, now we're going to do is
we're going to run this, okay? Make sure
you got your folder in here, and then
we're going to build out this template.
And what we're doing here is when you
repeat this over and over, what's going
to happen is you're going to start to
see the types of templates that work,
okay? And I'll show you after this how
we've done this personally. Like an
example is like in Rankability, we have
literally extracted, I don't know, a
couple thousand of local service pages
that are ranking number one on Google or
being pulled as a retrieval source in
AI. And what we did is we took all
thousand of those and built a structured
template that's proven to work for local
service pages.
We did the same thing for listicles. We
did the same thing for e-commerce
category pages, and we keep building
these over and over. So, we've just
We're doing Basically, what we've done
is what's happening right here, but
we've just done it at scale. Like we've
just done it a lot more. So, you know,
that saves time, obviously. But, this is
like if you're trying to keep everything
retained in this, this is how you have
to go about doing it. Now, could you
build out a little mini software where
you could go and do this? Certainly,
right? You could certainly do this a lot
faster, but for the sake of this, I'm
just showing you kind of the manual
slower way. But, you can always build a
little micro software solution to build
this out. Will that be easy? Will that
be worth it? That's for you to decide.
You know, I build software, so I'm just
telling you it's not fun to build
software and then maintain it and
iterate on it, okay? That's very hard.
People greatly underestimate how much it
takes to actually do that. It's really
easy these days to start software. It's
extremely hard to maintain software and
know what to do with that software and
be disciplined in developing that
software. There's so many little details
that you really don't understand until
you get deep into it. And once you're
deep into it, you realize, "Whoa, this
is much harder than I anticipated." And
that's just the nature of it. Okay, so
Claude is officially done analyzing the
asset and building out a template for
us. And you can see that right here. And
once again, you know, Opus just goes
major overkill. This is so extreme. And
the reality is you want to repeat this
over many assets to get to start to see
the commonalities for the structure of
pages that tend to perform well for the
intent of that topic. That is the key.
And so you can see here we've got that
reusable content template now. So
basically what I would do
is I would remove all that fluff that
Claude created and I would just create a
dedicated file specifically for this
type of content. So this would be like a
listical template, okay? And so every
time you create content, you run the
listical template. And then of course,
if your content is unique and you're
doing all the stuff you need to do, and
I'll show you later on in the series how
to do that, the template is the baseline
that you work from. Do not reinvent the
wheel. This is a big mistake. You
reinvent the wheel in other areas. You
bring in your experience. You bring in
your expertise. You bring in the unique
stuff that makes that content different
than everyone else and try to tap into
information gain. You want to do all
that. But what you don't want to do is
try to restructure the asset itself into
a structure that is not proven. This
structure works. We know that. It is a
fact. We see it with our own eyes. It
works. So you can certainly it is a
gamble to use a different structure,
okay? And especially when you have
enough evidence and enough data to prove
that. When you have
a couple hundred assets proving a
particular structure
over time, you are taking a massive
gamble, a massive bet if you try to do
something different, okay? So, like I
said, we're modeling the structure that
works. We're not copying the content. I
just want to make that clear. That's not
what we're doing. We're just building a
proper template and structure. So, I
would highly recommend rinsing and
repeating this for at least five to 10
different keywords and typically two to
three competitors per keyword. That'll
give you at least a nice little pool to
work with. Obviously, more is better.
So, that is how you build the SEO super
intelligence foundation. In the next
video in this series, I'm going to be
focusing on keyword research. But, I do
want to show you one thing real quickly.
As you can tell, a lot of this work we
did here today is quite time-consuming.
There's a lot of friction and honestly,
this is really only effective if you're
kind of working on one brand and maybe
you've got maybe one to two team
members. You could string things
together and kind of do this, but it is
kind of a duct tape solution and that's
why a lot of these things that we did
here today, I have personally worked on
these to streamline these and make it
easier for people. And so, Rank Ability
in particular handles most of this for
you, okay? You come in here and you
create a new client. You go ahead and
run this through. It builds all those
knowledge base artifacts for you
automatically. You don't even need to do
a single thing. You just literally enter
your domain, enter your brand name, and
then we build out all the artifacts, the
brand voice, everything for you
automatically, okay? And on top of it,
we bring in Google Search Console data,
okay? You can see here, this is the same
exact project I've been working on in
this video. You can see that we've got
this all piped in. In fact, when you go
into settings, you can see sources.
We've got those markdown files. We've
We've the brand voice already set up.
This is basically no work at all on your
end to do this. We're talking basically
just entering the domain and entering
the brand into the fields. That's all
the work you have to do. And on top of
it, it actually goes out and builds a
dedicated keyword research database for
you. Just when you set up the client
automatically. It's literally on the
house. You don't have to use any credits
to do this. So we just do this for every
client that you set up, okay?
But on top of that, you when you go in
here, you get that Google Search Console
data enriched in here already. And that
way when you go and create a chat, you
can go ahead and just run anything. So I
might do something like give me a SEO
plan for the week based on studying our
data.
So I might just do something like a very
simple prompt like this, and then it
will create a full plan for us using the
existing knowledge base, using all the
data, and also the memory that's within
this particular client project. This is
the big advantage here that Claude or
ChatGPT does not have, that Rankability
has, which is we store all of the memory
in this one client workspace. So when
you run these chats, it's also pulling
from that as well. So you can see it's
going to give us a full strategy that we
can work with. And there's a little
secret stuff in here that I haven't
actually told you yet, which is the
underlying layer here which I described
today, which is like getting that AI
intelligence layer. We have that AI
intelligence layer, but there's actually
something that's on top of that, which
is I've taken over 5 million tokens,
which is about 500 coaching calls. I've
taken, you know, I forgot the amount of
consulting calls, and over 300 SOPs, and
we distilled that down and bake that
into our model here. So when you're
working with this, you're working with
real experience, real expertise that you
literally cannot get anywhere else. It
does not exist anywhere else. This is
the only place where you can get this
level, okay? And so this isn't just
giving you like generic recommendations.
These are recommendations based on real
campaigns, real results, not just using
kind of AI slop ideas, okay? So, I
wanted to show you that because if
you're trying to streamline your work,
this is going to be the best solution.
If you're an agency and you're starting
to get more clients and you you have a
team, you got to start streamlining this
work a lot more. This is how you do it.
Plus, if you want to use Claude, you
actually can use Rankability. You can
use the MCP from Rankability. You could
even use the direct API and you can use
all the powerful tools within
Rankability inside of Claude, okay? So,
it's insanely powerful. So, I just want
to make sure I show you cuz I feel like
I'd be doing you a disservice if I had
you doing all this heavy lifting when
you could just basically tap a few
buttons and be done with it. So, if
you're interested, I'll have a link
below. If you want to book a call with
me personally, you can. We can kind of
work through what a campaign would look
like inside of Rankability. Love to hear
from you, but either way, in the next
video, we'll be talking about keyword
research. And once again, I will give
you full methods, full systems that
don't involve having to use Rankability.